[Music]
hi my name is yesper and today I'm going
to talk about what's new in the Cod
develop Initiative for business Central
2024 Wave
2 before we get started let's remind
ourselves what is codevelopment
again well C- development is the
business Central team's ambition to
jointly develop the BC business
application together with the partner
community and the initiative is hence
centered around the ultimate code
collaboration tool which of course is
GitHub now the end goal is to have
Microsoft Engineers develop the
application platform side by side with
Engineers from the business Central
Community and thereby accelerating the
development of the platform
significantly now that's all great but
why should you engage what can code
development do for you well for starters
um you can get help developing your
features have the product group or
members of the community uh look over
your code review your code you know help
maintain it um to improve the features
that your customers need more eyes on
the code means higher quality
architecture and fewer
boxs also you can strengthen your
customer's confidence in your features
by letting them become an inherent part
of the business application
Platform One shipped you can take
confidence in the fact that business
Central product group now owns the
support of your
code but there's
more you can also help outpace the
competition by contributing Futures to a
more of a more should we say fundamental
nature you will help make business
Central the obvious choice for new
potential customers you know do you
remember the saying Rising tide lifts
all boats well build your toll verticals
on the obvious choice for a business
solution you can also integrate your
apps more seamlessly into the business
application you know give your customers
a more integrated experience by adding
the right anchor points into the
application platform perhaps part of
your solution should be in the base
application and that will make your you
know extensions shine and and truly feel
like an integrated seamless
experience and last but certainly not
least you can establish yourself as
being an expert amongst the business
Central team and of course the
community leave a mark on the features
that are going into the product this
will not only support others in
achieving their goals but it might also
set you on a path to become more
recognized as a subject matter
expert become the one that others seek
out for guide
guidance so you see Cod development is
truly a win-win or as I usually
formulate it together we win but enough
of the talking here let's see what Cod
development actually has done for 2024
release Wave
2 I am happy to announce that again with
2024 Wave 2 we have set a new record for
the amount of community contributions
that we have shipped together with this
release with 2024 W 2 we have shipped no
less than 156 Community
contributions and we're talking about
everything you know from connectors over
horizontal capabilities business
features extensibility improvements Buck
fixes and paper cuts and yes there even
is a co-pilot feature amongst them you
know this is an absolutely outstanding
effort so thank you so much to everyone
who has contributed to this release
you see more than 60 of of these
contributions have actually been added
by just four community members who are
really leading the path here uh in the
co- development
initiative so coming in on place number
four is Stefan Sage from basil who made
10 contributions thank you a lot for
that
Stefan on spot number three we have
Thomas Capitan now an MVP from Fusion 5
and he has made 15 contributions to to
this
release on spot number two also a very
familiar name uh Killian Zid singer now
also an MVP from Prisma Informatica with
no less than 17 contributions and with
21 contributions we have Alexander
Drogan from Ellis retail gentlemen thank
you so much for contributing to this
release you have made a huge uh impact
on the upcoming 2024 release Wave 2
so now let's shift gears let's take a
look at what actually these
contributions could look like so I've
picked five demos for you here uh these
are not necessarily the biggest
contributions or even the best
contributions but I've picked those
because they really show what I believe
you know really makes a difference and
what should be coming in through um this
code collaboration platform for demo one
um I've picked Stefan Sage make the
manual setup page easier to browse
now we start in the old version actually
where we go to the manual setup page and
you see this extremely busy page with a
lot of uh lines and they're not sorted
in a way is really impossible to use
almost so what Stefan said was well I
can do better so he went in and in the
upcoming release this page now looks
like this it's nicely grouped it's way
less busy the page and you know you can
actually find the things that you would
like to set up which is a huge Advantage
obvious
viously so you know this is one thing of
course you could build your own pte to
do this but why would you right why not
remove this paper cut and make this
rather useless page useful for everyone
so it's a great contribution um in my
opinion now the next demo is also a
small thing uh it's a notification for
duplicate external documents and sales
made by Stefan
deani and in this case let's go into our
sales invoices and let's very quickly
just create a invoice
here and we enter the external document
number now let's say we go for a cup of
coffee and we come back and we see the
invoice lying next to us and we enter
again we say Hey you know I need to
enter this invoice well now you get a
small notification saying hey you
already entered this uh
invoice now again this is not a big
thing and you could probably implement
this at pte but why not make the product
better you know everyone would like to
avoid entering the invoice twice and
having to revert one of them so this
should just be something you know that
makes the product just seem more should
we say elegant um so a very very nice
contribution if you ask me Demo three um
now we're looking into a little bit of a
productivity tool or productivity
Improvement its default quantities for
GL accounts by
million again we will go into our sales
setup here um and now you will see that
there is actually the default GL account
quantity which is a new
setting so now when we go into sales
invoices and let's create again one for
customer 10,000 here now if you go to GL
account and let's just pick the office
supplies
here you'll see that the quantity is
defaulted now this may not seem like
much right but when you do this hundreds
of time every day and every single time
you have to enter the quantity one you
know this is just great that you can get
the product to default this value for
you it's again one of these small things
that just makes the product better demo
number four by Demetri katson um this is
co-pilot assisted setup of number Series
this actually has its own launch event
session because uh it's a little bit of
a bigger feature um but I quickly want
to show you you know just the gist of it
so let's say that we go into the
purchase and payable setup and number
series is not set up all right so we
need to set this up usually a rather
time cons doing task for us now if we go
into number series and I Now quickly
filter on purchase of course there are
none it's not set up but now rather than
manually entering line by line and
spending time on that we ask co-pilot to
help us we can prepare for next year we
can modify but for this demo let's just
create and we're going to create a
number series for the purchase
module and we hit generate and now you
know copilot does some things
thinking and before you know it it will
present us an entire list of all the
number series setups that we need for
the purchase module you can go in and
you can change things in here um but
let's just say you know this is just
fine it's exactly what we're looking for
so all right let's keep
this uh I Now quickly need to refresh my
filter here I see there we go everything
is set up for us and not only has it set
up the number series and the number
series Lines no if we go into our
purchase uh setup here again you'll see
it also did the setup for us so what
used to take you know forever to set up
can now be done in the glimpse of an eye
now this is just for number series but
it kind of sets the path for how one
could Envision that business Central is
going to be set up uh going forward with
the power of
co-pilot now one final demo that I have
for you is phone number for custom ship
to address by
Capitan um one more time we go into our
sales
orders and now actually we specify a
custom ship to
address and there we have a phone number
which is new and actually you know in
some countries this is a regulatory
requirement you need to be able to reach
um the the address to which the goods is
shipped so this field has been added by
quite a lot of Partners through pte or
through other apps
and you might think you know ah this is
no big deal you know um but actually in
order to add this one field
783 objects had to be modified so that
this field is carried through the
posting routines onto the reports and so
on and so forth and you know imagine
that you know everyone now has to add
this through a pte everyone has to do
this large uh job that actually takes a
couple of days to implement you know why
not just put it into the base product
and be done with it and focus on
something that is more worthwhile so I
hope you got a A Taste of which
contributions make sense but now um
let's take a look at which contributions
of which contributor will receive this
year's contribution hero award that's
this little
fell now every year we award one partner
or one person for having contributed
something that is out of the
ordinary back in
2022 dway uh w the award with a
SharePoint connector uh because this was
a horizontal capability that somewhat
set the path for many future
connectivity
contributions and last year Killian
cising I got the honor of receiving this
award not just because he contributed 22
code contributions which is outstanding
in itself but also because he was a very
Vigilant code reviewer and an evangelist
for this initiative um so that was very
well earned
and now in this year 2024 the winner
is Dimitri katson for his amazing work
on delivering the first ever co-pilot
co-developed feature suggest number
series now delivering this capability um
hasn't been easy you know having to
respect Microsoft's responsible AI
principles you know require some effort
giving you know that we want to deliver
safe trustworthy and ethical features
when using
co-pilot but dii hang in there and you
know he iterated over this code over and
over again and in the end he was able to
actually ship this amazing feature
together with 2024 Wave
2 so congratulations Dimitri and thank
you very much for this great
contribution now unfortunately I cannot
give Dimitri the award in person as he's
not here in the studio with me but I
envision when he receives the award it's
going to look like something like this
and that is what I had for you today so
I'm looking forward to seeing what
co-pilot brings to the table with our
2025 um releases and if you you know
feel like joining the fun a good place
to start is akms BC code development
where you'll find you know some
guidelines on how to get started um and
don't ever hesitate to reach out to me
you can find me on LinkedIn you can find
me on X or wherever you feel like
finding me um I'm always happy to help
and guide you so I hope to see you on
GitHub very soon thank you for listening
and goodbye